# ALBERTO JOSE GONZALEZ ESCALANTE

Date of Birth: 21/09/1986

Address: 108 Derrynane Square, Dorset Street, Dublin 1, Ireland

E-mail: agonza05@gmail.com / agonza05@outlook.com

Phone: +353-862518484 Nationality: Venezuelan

Project Engineer with experience planning and controlling a wide number of projects, from Core-Network installations to implementing a Satellite TV platform. Specialized in Project Management in the Telecom field

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# January 2013 - April 2015

Modern Educational Centre (Dublin, Ireland)

#### **Role Description**

Responsible for developing and maintaining the school's management system and IT equipment over different campuses

#### Responsibilities

# System Administrator

- System Administrator:
  - Developing, managing, debugging and maintaining the company's administration system (sales process, students' database, academic records, management reports, auditioning)
  - o Supporting the different departments on issues with the system
  - Providing first level support and escalating trough proper channels
- IT:
  - Ensuring smooth operation of IT equipment (PC, server, printers, projectors, network equipment, Internet) on all campuses
  - Providing support to the different departments on IT issues (software installations,
     OS maintenance, hardware installations, network equipment)
  - Solving and responding queries in a timely and efficient manner
  - Tracking and documenting issues regarding IT
  - o Keeping the inventory of IT equipment and consumables

### June 2012 - December 2013

Gonessa S.A. (Engineering Consultant), Caracas, Venezuela

#### **Role Description**

Responsible for planning the activities of the different projects and reporting the weekly progress to the clients

# Project Planner and Controller (Remotely)

#### Responsibilities

- Developing the project schedule (physical and financial delivery plans)
- Reporting the project's milestone, risks and deviations
- Managing timeliness and quality of projects
- Updating clients on project progression
- Organizing and distributing the workload, assigning tasks, defining priorities
- Developing the closure documentation of the project

### January 2009 - March 2012

CANTV (Telecommunications Service Provider), Caracas, Venezuela

### **Role Description**

Responsible for coordinating the team activities (operational departments, suppliers, functional departments, etc.) to achieve the project objectives on schedule

#### Responsibilities

- Organizing and distributing the workload, assigning tasks, defining priorities
- Scheduling of field teams against active projects
- Project planning, tracking and on time delivery
- Attending weekly meetings with peers and managers
- Disseminating information from meetings to the project team on a regular basis
- Communicating with sales and technical teams
- Updating clients on project progression
- Monitoring and tracking their projects
- Supporting the Project Leader

## Participation in the following projects

- Data-Network Plan (Installation of new access points for high-speed data services)
- Commutation Plan (Expansion of interconnection points with other carriers)
- New Lines Expansion Plan (Expansion of the network for residential services)
- Application and Server Adequacy (Ensuring corporate standards)
- Direct Television to Home (Implementation of a new satellite TV platform)

# **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

IELTS Corrificate	May 2014	
IELTS Certificate	Overall score: 7.5	
EDI Certificate of English	April 2013 - Duration: Thirty six weeks	
	European College of Management, Dublin, Ireland	
PMP Course Certificate	March 2012 - Duration: Eighty hours	
	Noguera KRP C.A., Caracas, Venezuela	
Telecommunications Engineer	January 2009 - Duration: Five years	
(Equivalent to NFQ Level 8)	"Andrés Bello" Catholic University, Caracas, Venezuela	

### SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE

SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE			
Experience in:	Knowledge of:	Other skills and aptitudes:	
<ul> <li>Networking and IP Technologies</li> </ul>	Server Management (Windows/Linux)	<ul> <li>Speaking Spanish</li> </ul>	
• Project Management (PMBOK)	Web programming (HTML/PHP/JS)	Delivery focus	
<ul> <li>Cloud and Virtualization Technologies</li> </ul>	Databases (SQL)	Team and change	
• Digital Television (DTV / DVB / H264)	Configuration of Switches and	management	
• Satellite Networks (RCS / SCPC)	Routers (Cisco / Juniper)	Excellent communication	
<ul> <li>Installation of network equipment</li> </ul>	Virtual Machine (VirtualBox /	skills	
<ul> <li>Wireless Networks (WiFi / WWAN)</li> </ul>	VMware / Citrix)	Willingness to travel	
<ul> <li>Mobile Technologies (GSM / UMTS)</li> </ul>	VoIP (Asterisk)	Issue prioritization	
• Implementation of test procedures	Mobile OS (Android, iOS)	Working under pressure	
• Planning in Microsoft Project		Attention to details	
<ul> <li>Proficiency in Microsoft Office</li> </ul>		Self-developing	
		Team working	

# Project Engineer